Have any of you here heard of shallow ref?
In case you haven't, shallow ref sounds actually a bit like what you think,
which is that take this, uh, we're gonna take this, that's where I,
back in database JSON. Okay.
Imagine for a moment here, and let's go to Mar sandbox here,
that we had, uh, my data, and it was a ref that was this giant object, right?
This is a lot of data, and the thing is that when you make it a ref,
it actually basically watches everything at a deep level.
So it signs reactivity pretty, basically watches everything at a deep level,
which, um, at first glance, you're probably like, oh, that sounds good.
That's what I want. And so for, I don't know, most people,
one of those performance, like, for this,
actually, this is even not even really that big, so it probably would have matter.
But you can imagine if you're dialing stuff from your database,
you're doing some sort of tests. You can be tens of thousands of records.
And the thing is is you don't always need deep reactivity.
Sometimes you just need to know whether the object, like, the, the giant object has changed.
Instead of the words, hence why it's called that.
So shallow ref is a helper method, just like ref, uh, from view.
And the difference being that when you're dealing with large sets of data,
or more importantly, you're not gonna be manipulating, like, deep reactivity.
And so this particularly comes into play with tests that I've seen most commonly.
The actually recommend just default to shallow ref, because then it's just basically view is
only looking at the top. They're not worried about the rest of it.
And so again, this is more of a technique for in the event.
You think that performance might be an issue, or you know, for a fact that you don't need
deep reactivity. There are some who would even venture to go as far to say that shallow
ref should be your default. Some would claim that. I don't think it needs to be that extreme.
I would say I have seen most unit tests, or, like,
intent as they do tend to be shallow ref, because it's usually just like render this object
and skip to the next thing, or if there's one piece, it really needs to be reactive.
They'll make that piece reactive. Uh, so I have seen people, people try to optimize performance
in that regard, but just know that this exists for you in the event that you've ever
like, um, ref definitely seems like overkill for this thing. Well, we got to cover shallow ref.
So we were gonna formally give this a name. We talked about this earlier, and I mentioned that
we had basically touched on this. And so it's this reminder. So I guess how many people have
further worked termed singleton. Okay? Great. Yeah. Because here's the thing. It's not a
view thing. It's a JavaScript thing. It's programming thing. Uh, and so, you know, for those who
are maybe haven't heard of it or knew to it before, essentially, it's as the things that it's a
single instance that is then shared with a bunch of things. And so this is why we saw earlier
in our code when we were using things like use week. This is an example of a singleton right here
because this constant is then basically cached. And then whenever it's brought into another
component, that same instance of weeks is then being referenced. And that's the reason why we get
that shared state.